eyeconic.com 2019-12-27

# HIPAA Privacy Policy | Eyeconic

### Overview

THIS NOTICE DESCRIBES HOW PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION (“PII”) AND/OR PROTECTED HEALTH INFORMATION (“PHI”) ABOUT YOU MAY BE COLLECTED, USED AND DISCLOSED BY EYECONIC (“EYECONIC”, “WE” OR “US”) WHEN USING [EYECONIC.COM](https://www.eyeconic.com/) (THE “SITE”) AND HOW YOU CAN GET ACCESS TO THIS INFORMATION. PLEASE REVIEW IT CAREFULLY.

### Notice Revisions

Eyeconic reserves the right to revise the terms of this Privacy Notice, and to make the revised terms effective for all PII and PHI that it maintains. If Eyeconic revises this Privacy Notice, we will make the revised notice available on the Site.

purpose

The purpose of this Privacy Notice is to:

  * Provide you with notice of Eyeconic’s information protection practices, and
  * Explain your rights as an individual about whom Eyeconic maintains information.

### I. Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

(a)      **Information You Provide.** When you register or interact with the Site, we may ask that you provide us with certain information to facilitate your use of the Site, such as your first name, last name, email, phone number, gender and date of birth. In case you decide to purchase product, we may ask you to provide additional information, such as your full address and credit card details and share your personal information with companies who help us in the fulfillment of your request. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide their services. For instance, we communicate your credit card details to a third party payment processor (Eyeconic does not store any credit card information). You will also be required to create a username and password to establish an account. Depending upon the activity, some of the information we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory, and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity.

(b)      **Technical Information Obtained from the Use of the Site.** We collect certain technical information automatically when you use the Site to facilitate our provision of the services, which information may include the domain from which you access the Site, the date and time you access the Site, what areas of the Site you access, the IP address, unique device identifier, and the type of device and/or web browser you use to access the Site.

(c)      **Cookies and Other Technologies.** We our service providers, and other third parties (such as Facebook) may use cookies, web beacons – also referred to as single-pixel gifs – and other storage technologies to improve the Site and its functionality, provide measurement services and target advertising. Cookies are identifiers that a website stores on your computer's hard drive to facilitate the interaction between your computer and the website. We use several types of cookies that have different purposes. We use cookies that are essential to the operation of the Site (e.g. allowing you to place items in the shopping bag and purchase these items or allowing us to identify you and provide you access to your user account). These essential cookies are either session or persistent cookies. Session cookies expire when you close your browser. Persistent cookies remain stored on your computer or device until you delete them manually or until they expire. Please see below on how to block or delete cookies.

Other cookies make your use of the Site easier (e.g. allowing us to remember you and your preferences upon your next visit to the Site when checking “Remember Me”), make the Site run more smoothly to make it easier for you to navigate and enhance the experience of our Site and help us to maintain a secure Site. These functionality cookies are persistent cookies and exclusive to this Site and cannot be obtained or read by other websites.

Web beacons are embedded in webpages and permit us to count users who have visited those pages and for other related Site statistics in a manner similar to the use of cookies (e.g., recording the popularity of certain Site content and verifying system and server integrity). Web beacons are not used to access your personal information on our Site; they are solely used to compile aggregated statistics concerning the use of our Site.

(d)      **Targeted Advertising.** Eyeconic and our advertisers may use technologies such as cookies and remarketing tags to gather information about your activities on this Site and other sites and to help us recognize you and serve you with advertisements that we believe are relevant to you and your interests. However, we do not tell our advertisers who you are.

Cookie ID’s are used to target Eyeconic advertising that is relevant to the Site, to control the frequency of ads shown to you, and to help us monitor, improve, and evaluate our online advertising and campaign performance. Google’s DoubleClick cookie is a persistent cookie and does not store or contain personally identifiable information. With your consent, information associated with the DoubleClick cookie may be added to your Google account.

This Site also uses a Facebook Tag API and Custom Audience Pixel Tags through similar use of cookieID’s to collect data about activities of users that are sent to Facebook to track conversions and to allow Eyeconic to create custom audiences for the products or service that Eyeconic may advertise on Facebook. This Facebook cookie is a persistent cookie and does not store or contain personally identifiable information.

We also use technology that enables us to understand how our Site or mobile applications are used and tools to enable the display of targeted advertisements to our users, including across devices. For example, this technology allows us to determine the probability that a desktop web cookie and a mobile device belong to the same user. The Drawbridge cookie is a persistent cookie and does not store or contain personally identifiable information.

Click on the links below to learn more about the privacy practices of DoubleClick by Google, Drawbridge and Facebook:

  * <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>
  * <https://drawbridge.com/privacy>
  * <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>

You can also opt out of the collection and use of information for advertisement targeting. Click on the link below to access a mechanism for exercising such choice:

<https://www.aboutads.info/choices>

(e)      **Website Analytics.** We also use or allow third parties to serve cookies on our Site. For example, we use Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics to assist us with website analytics such as evaluating the use and operation of our website so that we can continue to enhance the website and our services. These analytics cookies are so called performance cookies. All information collected by these cookies is aggregated and therefore anonymous. Click on the links below to learn more about the privacy practices of Google and Adobe:

  * <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

(f)      **Blocking Cookies:** Many browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser settings to stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting them. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell a user how to prevent the browser from accepting new cookies, provide notification if new cookies are received, or disable cookies altogether. You are always free to reject any cookies, but some customer-specific parts of our Site, such as (a) viewing personal insurance eligibility and coverage details; (b) viewing information on services and eyewear received; (c) viewing a dependent's benefit details; and, (d) use of the virtual try-on functionality, may not work properly in the event cookies are rejected.

### II. Protected Health Information (PHI)

### Eyeconic's Responsibilities

Eyeconic is required to abide by the terms of this notice currently in effect by:

  * Maintaining the privacy of your Protected Health Information,
  * Notifying you of any breaches of your unsecured Protected Health Information, and
  * Providing you with notice of our legal duties and privacy practices with respect to Protected Health Information.

### DEFINITIONS

#### Business Associate

A person or entity that uses Protected Health Information to perform a service for Eyeconic. These services may include, but are not limited to:

  * billing
  * claim processing
  * data entry

### Health Care Operations

Activities related to Eyeconic’s operations, including but not limited to:

  * claim transmission
  * customer issue resolution

### Payment

Transmission or processing of claims.

### Protected Health Information

Information relating to a patient’s past, present or future health or condition, the provision of health care to a patient, or payment for the provision of health care to a patient. Protected Health Information includes, but is not limited to:

  * patient name
  * Social Security number/member ID
  * service date
  * diagnosis information
  * claim information

### Treatment

The provision, coordination or management of vision care and related services by one or more vision care providers.

### III. PRIVACY PRACTICES

#### How Eyeconic Uses and Discloses Information About You

**(a) Personally Identifiable Information:**

(i)     We use information collected from and about you, individually or combined, to facilitate use of the Site, process your purchases and related payments, communicate with you, respond to your inquiries and requests, conduct surveys, carry out research and analysis relating to our products and services, improve our products and services, and, as permitted by law, for marketing and promotional purposes. From time to time, we may send users administration communications about our services (for example, if you lose your password or if changes are made to the terms of the services or our privacy notice). Because this information is important to your interaction with and our provision of the Site, you may not opt-out of receiving such communications. We may also give you the option of receiving marketing communications about new products, services and promotions from Eyeconic, our affiliates and subsidiaries, or other third parties. If you choose to receive such marketing communications, we will share your contact information with the applicable third parties for this purpose. We may enhance or merge the information that we collect with data obtained from third parties, in which case the combined information will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

(ii)      **Third Party Channel Partners.** On occasion we partner with third parties to deliver complementary or supplemental services to you. In those circumstances, we will make it very clear to you that the third party channel partner is the entity collecting your information and not Eyeconic, and you will have a choice whether to provide information to them. As such, any data you provide to them would be subject to their privacy and security practices and Eyeconic will not be responsible for the information you provide to them or their privacy and security practices. An example hereof is the Virtual Try-On tool available on our Site. In order to provide you with this service, we have partnered with Ditto Technologies Inc.

Click [here](https://www.ditto.com/privacy-policy/) to learn more about Ditto’s privacy practices.

(iii)      **Affiliate Sharing.** Subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice, in the normal course of performing services, and as permitted by applicable law, we may share your information with our affiliates, subsidiaries, or divisions. For example, Eyeconic collects and shares certain information with [www.vsp.com](https://www.vsp.com/) to provide personalized features such as eligibility information of your VSP vision care benefit.

(iv)      **Sharing with Other Users.** Certain features of our Site may enable you to connect and communicate with other Site users (“Friends”). By participating in any sharing program, your information (including any personal information you provided, and any information obtained from the Site) may be made available to those Friends. Some Site sharing programs allow you to publish information in a forum, or transmit communications to Friends. Any information you choose to provide in these areas can be read or used by other users. You are solely responsible for any information that you choose to share. Your participation in these features and your sharing of your information with us and other users constitutes your agreement to such sharing. Please take care when using these features.

(v)      **Children.** Eyeconic doesn't sell products for purchase by children. We sell children's products for purchase by adults. If you're under 18, you may use Eyeconic only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

**(b) Protected Health Information:**

Eyeconic will only use and disclose your PHI without your authorization when necessary for:

  * coordination of your vision care treatment
  * disclosure to your plan sponsor to the extent permitted by law
  * payment
  * health care operations, or
  * as required or permitted by law (please see “Use or Disclosure Required or Permitted by Law” section).

### Disclosure to Eyeconic’s Business Associates

Eyeconic will only disclose your PHI to Business Associates who have agreed in writing to maintain the privacy of PHI as required by law.

### Use or Disclosure Requiring Authorization

Eyeconic will not use or disclose your PHI for purposes other than those described in this notice. If it becomes necessary to disclose any of your PHI for other reasons, Eyeconic will request your written authorization. Eyeconic will obtain your authorization for any sale of PHI, to use or disclose your PHI for marketing. Revoking Authorization: If you provide written authorization, you may revoke it at any time in writing, except to the extent that Eyeconic has relied upon the authorization prior to its being revoked.

### Use or Disclosure Required or Permitted by Law

Eyeconic may use or disclose your Protected Health Information to the extent that the law requires the use or disclosure:

  * _Public Health:_ For public health activities or as required by the public health authority.
  * _Health Oversight:_ To a health oversight agency for activities such as audits, investigations and inspections. Oversight agencies include, but are not limited to, government agencies that oversee the health care system, government benefit programs, other government regulatory programs and civil rights laws.
  * _Legal Proceedings:_ In response to an order of a court or administrative tribunal, in response to a subpoena, discovery request or other lawful process.
  * _Law Enforcement:_ For law enforcement purposes, including: 

\- legal process or as otherwise required by law;  
\- limited information requests for identification and location;  
\- use or disclosure related to a victim of a crime;  
\- suspicion that death has occurred as a result of criminal conduct;  
\- if a crime occurs on Eyeconic’s premises; or  
\- in a medical emergency where it is likely that a crime has occurred.  

  * _Criminal Activity:_ As requested by law enforcement authorities, if the use or disclosure is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to the health or safety of a person or the public.

### Use and Disclosure Examples

  * _Payment:_ Eyeconic uses Protected Health Information for payment processing to verify that services provided were covered under the patient’s vision care plan.
  * _Health Care Operations:_ Eyeconic uses and discloses Protected Health Information to audit and review claims payment activity to ensure that claims were paid correctly.
  * _Treatment:_ To coordinate treatment by a health care provider.

### Personal Representative

Eyeconic may disclose your Protected Health Information to a person who has legal authority to make health care decisions on your behalf.

### Disclosure Requiring Opportunity to Object

Eyeconic may disclose your Protected Health Information to a family member, friend, or other person involved in your care or payment if the information is relevant to their involvement and you have agreed or had an opportunity to object.

### Genetic Information

Eyeconic is prohibited from using or disclosing your genetic information for underwriting purposes.

### KNOW YOUR RIGHTS

#### Exercising Your Rights

You may exercise any of your below rights by sending us a written request.

#### Review Your PII or PHI

You have a right to inspect and obtain a copy of your PII or PHI.  
_Important:_ If you feel your PII or PHI is incomplete or incorrect, you have the right to request that it be amended. 

#### Request to Restrict Your PHI

You can request restrictions on the use and disclosure of your PHI. Eyeconic is not required to agree to a requested restriction.

_Example:_ If a restriction request prevents us from providing service to you or from performing payment related functions, we will not be able to agree to the request.

#### Confidential Communication

When necessary, Eyeconic may seek to contact you by calling you at your home or by sending mailings containing your Protected Health Information to your home. If you feel that such communications could compromise your safety, you may request in writing an alternate communication method and/or location.

#### Accounting of Disclosures

If a disclosure of your Protected Health Information was made for a reason other than treatment, payment or health care operations, you have a right to receive an accounting of the disclosure.

_Important:_ If the disclosure was made to you, Eyeconic will not provide an accounting.

#### Receive a Copy of Complaints

You can view and print a copy of this Privacy Notice through Eyeconic.com. If you believe that your privacy rights have been violated, you may submit a complaint to Eyeconic or to the U.S. Secretary of Health and Human Services at any time. Eyeconic will not retaliate against you for filing a complaint. You may file a complaint with Eyeconic at Eyeconic.com.

### CONTACT INFORMATION

#### Contact Eyeconic

For questions about this notice or your privacy, contact us at 1-855-EYECONIC (1-855-393-2664) or [info@eyeconic.com](mailto:info@eyeconic.com). Our hours are Monday to Friday, 7:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. PT.
